Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
www.opensubtitles.org Original
Sub By ViKramJS Resync By M_I_S
[dramatic drum beat]
["Mission: Impossible"
theme playing]
[man. in Russian]
Mission report
Russian Federation
submarine K599 Sevastopol.
Operation: Podkova
day 74
[man. in English] The active
learning defense system testing...
continues to operate flawlessly.
[man continues in English]
One might even say...
miraculously.
We are navigating under
the Arctic ice cap
by dead reckoning and
five days from home.
After 25.000 nautical miles.
the Sevastopol has
deliberately approached
every navy in the world
and remained
completely undetected.
The Podkova's stealth capability
has exceeded all expectations.
We are at this moment the
state of the art of war.
The most fearsome
killing machine
ever devised by man.
And we are impossible to find.
Captain. we have a submerged
contact. designated Semyon-83.
exhibiting tonals of a US
Virginia-class submarine.
Bearing 130°. drawing forward.
Chief of the Watch. man
battle stations silently.
Wait for orders.
Officer of the
Deck. ship status?
Ship's depth. 50 meters.
Bottom. 72 meters.
Clearance to the ice
canopy. 21 meters.
Distance to deep
water? Two kilometers.
Aleutian Precipice
in six minutes.
Ranging maneuver. Helm.
left 15 degrees rudder.
Steady course 100°.
Come up easy on a standard bell.
Captain has the
conn. Helm. aye!
Coming to course 100°.
[tonals fluttering]
Steady on course 100°.
Weapons Officer. range?
Firing solution is tracking at
a distance of 15.000 meters.
Sir. that doesn't make sense.
Tonals this loud and clear?
[tonals continue] He
must be closer than that.
[beep]
Captain. firing solution
just did a step change
to 10.000 meters.
Nothing moves that fast.
All solutions are matching.
The range is true.
Helm. right full
rudder to course 270°.
Course 270°. aye.
We'll just walk away
and head for deep water.
Contact bearing 160°.
Bearing rate zero?
He's there. turning
with us again.
He can see us.
Impossible. We're invisible.
Weapons. run diagnostics
on sonar and fire control.
Something isn't right.
Sir. he's flooding
his torpedo tubes!
Torpedo room. conn.
Load all torpedo
tubes. Aye. sir.
Check clear! Forward clear!
Aft clear! Ram
torpedo! Ramming!
Torpedo tubes loaded.
He's opened outer doors!
Weapons. flood tubes one through
four and open outer doors.
Enter firing solution
into tube two.
Aye. Captain. Making tube
two ready in all respects.
Captain. he's provoking us.
He wants an excuse to
blow us out of the water.
Enemy torpedo in the
water. bearing 200°.
1.000 meters and accelerating.
Helm. left full rudder.
all ahead flank cavitate.
My rudder is left full.
Answering all ahead
flank cavitate.
Launch countermeasures.
Launching countermeasures.
Fire tube two.
Firing tube two.
[dramatic music]
Our torpedo is
away. Running hot.
Enemy torpedo still
homing. range 800 meters.
He's blown through
our countermeasures.
Helm. right full
rudder. Right full.
Aye. sir! 600 meters.
Diving Officer. stand by to emergency
blow all main ballast tanks.
400 meters. Chief of the Watch.
stand by the collision alarm.
200 meters. This
is the captain.
All hands brace for impact.
Enemy torpedo impact in...
five... four...
three... two...
one. Impact!
[silence]
[exhales]
What just happened?
It's. it's gone.
It missed us?
No.
It vanished like
it was never there.
Sonar. where is
the enemy vessel?
Bearing 330°.
4.000 meters off
our starboard bow.
Our torpedo is running true.
Impact with enemy
submarine in...
three... two... one.
[sonar pinging]
Where was the impact?
Captain. enemy
submarine has vanished.
It's gone. sir.
I don't understand.
He was never there.
We've been chasing a phantom.
It was right there. The
instruments don't lie.
They lied to us today.
Weapons. shut down our
torpedo. Aye. Captain.
Shutting down torpedo.
Secure from battle stations.
[suspenseful music]
This is why we have sea trials.
There's a bug in the system.
[button clicks]
A ghost in the machine.
[sighs] It's time
to go home. Captain!
Our own torpedo
is not responding.
It's coming right at us!
Our torpedo's homing.
range 400 meters!
Oh. my God. Wire command.
Shut down our weapon!
Our torpedo's still
closing. range 200 meters!
Blow all main ballast tanks!
Sound the collision alar...
[dramatic music]
[sputtering]
[slow instrumental music]
[door closes]
Food delivery.
Hello?
Designator.
Easy.
India-Zulu-254.
Bravo-Echo-11.
No. not yet.
You need to ask me the
security question first.
Oh. yeah. Sorry.
Uh...
what is the oath?
We live and die
in the shadows...
for those we hold close...
and for those we never meet.
You can put it on the table.
Hey.
Welcome to the IMF.
You made the right choice.
Sir.
[man on recording]
Good evening. Mr. Hunt.
It's been a long time.
Our lives are the
sum of our choices.
and we cannot escape the past.
Thirty years ago. you
were offered the choice.
Join the IMF or spend
your life in prison.
Because of your unique
natural talents.
your government forgave you.
But we will never forget.
Just as you will
never forget the death
that brought you to us
all those years ago.
[soft music]
This is to remind you
of your oath and
allegiance to us.
The stakes of this mission
are higher than ever.
Your habitual rogue behavior
will not be tolerated.
Should you choose to accept.
it is imperative
that you listen.
Your government is
searching for a key.
Its purpose. its
vital importance to us
is none of your concern.
What should concern you
is the involvement of
your friend Ilsa Faust.
She killed a
courier in Istanbul.
And we believe he
was carrying one half
of the key we're searching for.
Why she has chosen to interfere
in this affair is a mystery.
as are her whereabouts.
What is certain
is that your government has
put a price on her head...
and these bounty hunters
are out to collect it.
They never bring a
fugitive back alive.
and rarely in one piece.
We believe they're headed for the
Arabian Desert's Empty Quarter
in search of your friend.
Find the bounty hunters.
and you may just find her.
Your mission. should
you choose to accept it.
is to acquire the key
and deliver it to us.
What happens to Ilsa
after that is up to you.
As always.
if any members of your
team are caught or killed.
the secretary will disavow
any knowledge of your actions.
This message will
self-destruct in five seconds.
Good luck. Ethan.
[foreboding string instrumental]
Come.
[gentle music]
[wind whistling]
[bird cries in distance]
[gunfire in distance]
[wind whistling]
Ethan.
[horse whinnies. blusters]
[music flares]
[gunfire]
Hyah! Hyah!
[gunfire continues]
[horse whinnies] [blows]
[gunshot]
[wind howling]
Ohh!
[wind dies down]
So what are we dealing with?
This "entity" has
multiple personalities.
at times behaving
like a computer virus.
then a tapeworm. then a botnet.
Distorting any and all
digital information
with which it comes in contact.
Once infected. nothing
recorded. stored.
or transmitted digitally
can be trusted as fact.
At the outset. it concentrated
primarily on news and social media
which was of little
concern to us
as it often suited our purposes.
Until six months ago.
when the entity breached
Saudi Arabia's General
Intelligence Directorate.
And assimilated their top
secret active-learning AI
before vanishing into the cloud.
Subsequent attacks increased
ten-thousandfold overnight.
spreading exponentially.
Indicating that the
Entity has since become
sentient.
You're telling me this
thing has a mind of its own?
[woman] Over the last
three weeks alone.
it has accessed our
satellite telecommunications.
the Federal Reserve.
the stock market.
and the national power grid.
[man] The FAA. NASA
and the combined
branches of our military.
[man 2] And we're not alone.
It has penetrated the World
and European Central Banks.
[man 3] Gained entry
to the major defense.
finance and
infrastructure systems
of Russia. India. Israel.
Australasia. all of Europe.
[Denlinger] And what did it do
to all these systems exactly?
Nothing.
Nothing? It came and it went.
leaving fingerprints where
they could easily be found
and sending a very
clear message.
"I shall return."
Whatever its ultimate goal is.
we're powerless to stop it.
The full force of its
energy is now directed
at a single objective.
The world's
intelligence networks.
The very truth as we know it.
[man 2] The entire intelligence
community is racing
to archive hard copies
of our fact-positive
knowledge bases
before our most
secure data centers
are breached and corrupted.
[man 3] Which is only
a matter of time.
[man 1] The Entity will know precisely
how to undermine our every strength
and exploit our every weakness.
How to turn our
allies into enemies
and our enemies into aggressors.
Why not air-gap our
intelligence servers?
Cut them off from the
outside world entirely?
We already have.
But servers require
humans to maintain them.
[man] And humans are the weakest
link in any security chain.
especially when dealing with a
godless. stateless. amoral enemy.
[man 2] One that has
been patiently listening.
reading. watching.
Harvesting our deepest
personal secrets for years.
Able to beguile. blackmail.
bribe or be anyone it wants.
And to manipulate us at will
through our total dependence
on a carefully constructed
digital reality.
An enemy that is everywhere...
[whispers] and nowhere...
and has no center.
All right.
so what you're telling me is the
most awesome goddamn intelligence
and tactical apparatus
on the planet
has no way of
killing this thing.
You don't want to kill it. sir.
You want to control it.
And how do we do
that. Mr. Kittridge?
The CIA's assets in
the Kremlin informed us
that the Russians have focused
the majority of their
intelligence activity
on acquiring two halves
of a cruciform key.
And what does it unlock?
Not exactly sure.
But the Russians seem to
believe that it somehow has
the power to deactivate
our mysterious Entity.
Though. ideally...
they hope to control
it. harness it.
Do you believe that. Kittridge?
What matters is that the rest
of the world believes it.
Japan. India. Germany.
and the Brits believe it.
and yet no one. not
even our closest allies.
have willingly whispered
one word of it to us.
Which would indicate that
there's a global race on
to acquire the two
halves of this key.
Every nation in
it for themselves.
not to kill this thing. sir.
but to weaponize it.
And in so doing.
establish a new. incontestable
form of global dominance.
How do we find this key first?
Well. we know that a buyer is passing
somewhere through the Middle East
sometime in the next 72 hours.
We believe that he already
has one half of this key.
You believe. [Kittridge]
At this point.
we can't be certain
it's not a counterfeit.
How would you verify that?
The only thing that can authenticate
one genuine half of the key
is the other genuine
half of the key.
Its true mate. if you will.
We think it's some
sort of fail-safe.
How do we find its mate?
Well. we believe the other
genuine half of the key
was in the hands of this woman.
Who is she?
Ilsa Faust.
[man 3] Former
British Intelligence.
Where is she now?
She's dead. sir.
She was... [clears
throat] excuse me...
killed by mercenaries
looking to collect a bounty.
And who put up the bounty?
Given her body of work.
could have been anyone.
So anyone could have
her half of the key?
Hmm. not just anyone.
I sent a man to find her.
the only man she
would have entrusted
with her half of the key.
Does he have it. Kittridge?
Well. at present. I
don't know that. sir.
He's refused to come in.
Refused? [Kittridge] Hmm.
Who the hell is this guy?
That's classified.
I'm the goddamn Director
of National Intelligence.
What exactly is it I'm not
supposed to know about?
The IMF. Mr. Kittridge.
The world bank. No. that's the
International Monetary Fund.
Mr. Kittridge.
No. I mean the
other IMF. Ours.
What does it stand for?
Impossible Mission Force.
You're not serious.
[woman] I'm afraid he is.
And what do they do exactly?
It's just as the name implies.
Whatever the rest of us can't.
And who is in charge? They're
not ones to take orders
in the traditional sense.
We more or less...
leave word.
Leave... word.
Mr. Kittridge. sir.
The IMF operates
outside the community
and answers directly
to the president.
So let me get this straight.
When there's a mission
none of you can handle...
you just leave word
for a nameless man
and hope he gets the job done.
Is that it?
Should he choose to accept it.
What the hell kind of outfit
gets to choose what
orders to accept?
The IMF was expressly created
to ensure there would be
no unintended consequences.
If they cannot ensure a
mission's ultimate outcome.
they're authorized to decline.
[epic music]
[portentous instrumental beat]
[heroic orchestration of
"Mission: Impossible" theme]
I understand.
You're upset.
I'm not upset. Kittridge.
You wanted me to listen.
This is me listening.
[whispering] All right.
[normal voice] I put the
bounty on Ilsa's head.
I also told you how to find her!
I didn't ask her
to steal the key.
She did that for reasons
of her own. But...
that's the pattern. isn't it?
You get her out of trouble.
and she always found
her way back in.
[sighs]
[grunts] Wait! Ilsa!
Ilsa. wait! It's me! What?
It's me.
It's okay.
[soft music]
Listen to me! You're
dead! You stay dead!
Ethan. wait!
I'm not going to
apologize to you. Hunt.
It's my job to use you.
Just like it's your
job to be of use.
Did you accomplish your
mission [whispers] or not?
Wherever the other
half of this is.
whatever the
completed key unlocks.
I will find it.
And then what?
No one should be trusted
with control of the Entity.
I mean to kill it.
Ethan.
the next world war isn't
gonna be a cold one.
It's gonna be a shooting war.
it's gonna be a ballistic war over
a rapidly shrinking ecosystem.
It's gonna be a war for the
last of our dwindling energy.
drinkable water. breathable air.
Whoever controls the
Entity controls the truth.
The concepts of right and wrong
can be clearly defined for
everyone for centuries to come.
Do you even hear yourself?
Your days of fighting for
the so-called greater good
are over.
You need to pick a side.
I'm on the same side
I've always been on.
Stay out of my way.
I can't do that.
We're gonna be coming after you.
The world's gonna
be coming after you.
And one way or another.
this mission of yours
[whispers] is gonna
cost you dearly.
[phone rings]
[rings]
If I don't get that. we're
gonna have company real soon.
[rings]
Hello?
[man] Director
Denlinger. please.
Uh. Director is
unavailable at the moment.
How can I help you?
To whom am I speaking?
CIA Director Eugene Kittridge.
Designator?
"Bassnote." lowercase.
all one word.
Sir. we have a situation.
No kidding.
Your adjutant was
found unconscious
in his home ten minutes ago.
It appears he was drugged.
I understand.
I don't think you do. sir.
Security has him
entering this facility
fifteen minutes ago. I
understand. thank you.
Are you able to speak freely?
No. thank you.
A security team is on their way.
If you're in any danger.
simply hang up the phone
before I count to five.
One. two...
[phone clatters]
So just how do you plan
on getting out of here?
Of course.
[gunshot] [grunts]
["Mission: Impossible"
theme playing]
Listen up.
An American operative with a
grievance against his country
is missing and
has malfunctioned.
His agenda represents a threat
to our national interests.
and he must be
neutralized at all cost.
Anything in this
man's possession
is of vital importance and
must be captured intact.
The man himself is expendable.
He is not to be underestimated.
A master of
infiltration. deception.
sabotage and psych warfare.
For all intents and purposes.
ladies and gentlemen.
a mind-reading. shape-shifting
incarnation of chaos.
So. for your safety
and the safety of
those around you.
do not consider him secure
unless you have driven a wooden
stake through his open heart.
This is not a drill.
A self-aware. self-learning.
truth-eating digital parasite
infesting all of cyberspace.
[gasp] Well. it was bound
to happen sooner or later.
And the two halves of this
key just might provide
the means of
controlling this Entity.
Meaning every government
on the planet would kill us
just to get that key.
Including our own.
Exactly.
Putting us on an
unsanctioned mission
which has gone rogue
before it even started.
Meaning this very conversation
is technically an
act of treason.
Or as we like to
call it. Monday.
So what's the play?
A buyer's coming in on
Flight 746 from Amsterdam
for a 30-minute layover
at which time he is hoping to
purchase that half of the key.
And it stands to reason
the buyer will have the other half
of the key somewhere on their person.
Being the only way to
authenticate our half.
So how do we identify the buyer?
This Geiger counter will
detect a radiological signature
of the dragon's egg
embedded in the buyer's key.
The augmented-reality
overlay in these glasses
will lead us to it.
[laughs]
Oh. that's very clever.
So. you ID the buyer.
pick his pockets.
Bob's your uncle. No.
No. Of course not.
The complete key is of no value
if we don't know
what it unlocks.
So you're going
to sell the buyer
our half of the key.
While we figure out the
buyer's connecting flight
and book you a
seat on that plane.
So you can follow the
key wherever it goes.
Which you hope is into the hands
of someone who knows
what it unlocks.
Precisely.
Finding the completed key
is only the beginning.
The fate of the world
depends on finding
whatever it unlocks.
This guy. you know him?
Not personally.
But it is personal.
[action adventure music]
[quieter music]
Thank you.
Hey. what's that? What?
Security alert. Suspicious
bag on its way to Venice.
Nope. it's gone. Must
have been a false alarm.
[suspense music]
Overwatch. Snap
Shot. Where's he at?
Snap Shot. Overwatch.
I have him.
Terminal B. Gate
15. headed south.
I am so. You are not.
Ethan. would you care to explain
to our friend the Net Ranger
how I am just as capable
of writing code as he is?
No comment.
What. you figure
Phineas Phreak here
is gonna single-handedly work
out a way to kill the Entity
while I just hold
his soldering iron?
Probably. Definitely.
Out of the way! [men shouting]
Tell me where he is.
Where is he? Blue suit.
Right in front of you.
Oh! [speaks Italian]
[continues speaking Italian]
Oh! Ah! Ow! [gurgling]
[speaking Italian]
It's not him.
It's him.
I'm telling you. it's not him.
And I'm telling you
facial comes back
with a perfect...
How did you do that?
[whispers] No one is
safe from Phineas Phreak.
[beeps] I got him.
Where is he?
Terminal E. Gate 5.
Goddamn it. that's clear on
the other side of the airport.
[man speaking Italian]
[Luther] Ethan. they're
headed to Terminal E.
That side of the
airport is all yours.
Thank you. Luther.
I see the buyer. Got him.
The buyer is Otto Von
Bork. Swiss national.
He's connecting to Venice.
departing in 30
minutes on Flight 1031.
Benji. get me on that
flight to Venice.
Yep. Flight 1031 to
Venice. Stand by.
[beeping]
What?
[Luther] Ethan.
what just happened?
He was bumped. Bumped?
What do you mean. bumped?
That woman picked
his pocket. Tag her.
Tell me who she is.
[suspense music]
[beeping]
Luther. mute our comms.
What is it?
That bag was on its
way to Flight 1031.
What bag?
There was a suspicious bag
alert. a few minutes ago.
So what about it?
It was on its way
to Flight 1031.
To Venice. It's
the buyer's plane.
It's Ethan's plane.
Luther. do you copy? Who is she?
What if it wasn't a false alarm?
What if somebody's trying to
smuggle a bomb onto that plane?
And what if that's what the
Entity wants us to think
to keep Ethan off that plane?
[Ethan] Luther. what's
happening? Should we warn him?
No. Guys. guys?
Do you hear me?
Find that bag.
I'll direct you. Go.
Luther. just tell me. is
there something wrong?
Nothing to worry about.
It's under control.
Got her.
Info on the woman is coming now.
[Luther] Whoa.
Whoever she is. she's no spy.
She's a thief.
[Benji] Where am
I going. Luther?
Benji. there's a door
on your immediate left.
I'm unlocking it now.
The bag you're after
is on tray 01833
heading towards the northwest
corner of the facility.
Copy that!
[slight gasp]
Hi.
Hello.
Oh. I get it.
You thought I was someone else.
[sighs]
I'm not interested.
Give me a chance.
I'll scream.
Please do.
[suspense music]
What do you want?
This key.
The one you picked
from that man's pocket.
It's worthless
without this key.
But together
they're worth four
million in cryptocurrency
that man was carrying
on a flash drive.
Well. I wouldn't know
anything about that.
Then why was this
drive in your pocket?
Who are you?
You working with someone?
Never. I'm strictly single-0.
Today you got a partner.
I need the man you
stole this from
to complete a transaction
and leave this airport
with both of these
without ever knowing
his pocket was picked
and before he boards
his flight in...
[Luther] Seven
minutes. Seven minutes.
We both know you're
a good pickpocket.
Let's see what kind
of put-pocket you are.
You expect me to put it back.
Oh. I know you will.
You're a thief.
You want the money. And
I can give it to you.
Your choice.
You're in or you're out.
All right.
So what's the play?
[Luther] I sure hope you
know what you're doing.
After you.
Oh. I won't be needing this.
I don't smoke.
Keep it. Something
to remember me by.
Ethan. the alloy in that key she
took off the buyer doesn't match.
It's counterfeit.
I expect nothing less.
But that doesn't
change our objective.
The buyer has to
leave with both keys.
Talk to me. Luther!
Where am I going?
Benji. head down the
stairs in front of you
and the bag should
be right there.
Okay. I'm there. I'm there.
Uh...
That's him.
Right in front of you.
Okay. okay. Hey. sorry.
Thought you were somebody else.
Hunt's jerking our chain.
Everybody! Two-man
teams. spread out.
Ethan. our American
friends are getting wise.
They're breaking up and
canvassing the airport.
Keep your eyes peeled.
So. what do I call you?
How about Grace? And you?
Well. listen. Grace.
You should know we're not
the only interested party.
If I tell you to run. you run.
Run?
This is getting exciting.
Benji. have you got that bag?
I found it!
There's a cylindrical
device inside.
I'm gonna take it out.
[Ethan] How we doing. Luther?
Ethan. the buyer's in the
waiting area above you.
Top of the escalator.
All units are headed
in your direction.
Your location is going to
be crawling with agents
any time now.
[suspenseful music]
Whatever it is. I've
just activated it.
Uh. looks like we have
five minutes. [beep]
Also. it appears to
be nuclear. How big?
Big enough to matter to everybody
in this airport. I suspect.
Can you disarm it? I
haven't got any tools!
Then find some. Where
am I gonna find...
[dramatic music]
Is this where we run?
Not yet.
Benji. how are you
doing with that bomb?
Come on. come on.
I got it!
It's a cylinder cypher.
There's eight wheels.
Looks like 14 letters
on each wheel.
1.5 billion possible
combinations.
Give or take.
Oh. my God.
What now?
The wheels. they
spell out a message.
U.R.DUNN.
No way. Not yet we aren't.
No. Luther. not D-O-N-E.
D-U-N-N.
It's my last name.
It knows who I am.
[ominous music]
Hold on. There's a
message on the display.
"I speak without a mouth.
I fly through the
air without wings.
What am I?" You got me. What?
It's a riddle. I suspect this
thing is voice-activated.
It wants me to say the answer.
"I fly through the air..."
An echo!
That's it! That's it!
Okay. new message.
"Are you afraid of death?"
What kind of a riddle is
that? It's not a riddle.
It's a psychometric test.
The more questions you answer.
the more it'll know about you.
"Are you afraid of death?" No!
Did it work? I lied. It knows.
Just tell it the truth. Say it.
"Are you afraid of
death?" Yes! Who isn't?
Pardon.
Okay. "What's always approaching
but never arrives?" Um...
Wait. I know this one.
The clock is ticking. Luther.
Riddles aren't my thing.
Benji. What more can I say?
We're running out of time!
There he is. Oh.
this is too easy.
Sorry to bother you. Ethan.
Would you happen to know
what's always approaching
but never arrives?
What is always approaching
Tomorrow.
What?
Always approaching but
never arrives: Tomorrow.
It's tomorrow. Tomorrow.
Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
Yes! Okay. next question.
Give me the goods.
I'll be watching.
Why. you don't trust me?
Luther. what is happening?
Nothing to worry about.
Everything is under control.
Okay. next question:
"Who or what is the most
important thing to you?"
Say it. But if I...
There's no other
choice. Say it.
My friends.
Bastard.
Is he... Yes. he is.
Give me the money.
give me the key.
Okay. "What gets bigger
the more you take away?"
A hole. A hole. Brilliant!
I've got no more questions
and there's one more wheel.
How am I supposed to give
answers if I've got no questions?
That must be your final test.
I've got 45 seconds!
What happens now?
I'm thinking. Don't move.
Luther. I'm pinned
down. Need a way out.
Where am I going?
We have a bigger problem. Ethan.
It's very possible no one
is getting out of here.
What? There's a bomb
in baggage handling.
A nuclear bomb.
The question I asked you
is part of the code
for disarming it.
Stop. stop. stop. stop.
Why didn't you tell me this?
You had a lot going on. We
didn't want to bother you.
Listen to me. A nuclear bomb is
something you bother me with immediately.
How much time? Twenty seconds.
Twenty seconds?
There's one more riddle.
I'm working on it.
Fifteen seconds!
Easy. easy. What's the riddle?
In the time it takes me to
explain. we'll all be dead!
Come on. Benji. Why
do we always end up
in these situations?
Ten seconds.
Nine... eight...
seven... six... five...
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
[Benji] Oh. my God.
What is it?
It's empty.
What do you mean. empty?
There's nothing inside.
[suspense music]
She took the key.
Which key?
Our key. The real key.
What? Luther. find her.
I got her. She's
headed for Terminal E.
[eerie music]
No. it can't be.
What is it?
Luther. Benji. Abort. Get out!
Where do we
rendezvous? We don't!
This mission is
terminated. Get out now.
Hunt! Stop right there!
Hey! You see him? Where is he?
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
[dramatic music]
Move!
Move! Move. move!
He's got to be here somewhere.
Goddamn.
[action adventure music]
What we have here
is shortwave radio.
magnetic audio recording.
cathode ray tube monitors.
No more ones and zeros.
It's a fully analog.
offline safe room.
shielded from our
digitally-based Entity.
Where is this feed coming from?
CORONA spy satellite
from the Cold War.
Had no idea we were
still using those things.
Yeah. well. we weren't.
Gave them to the National
Weather Service 20 years ago.
This is the last one
still functioning.
So. will this thing help us
find your nameless IMF man?
Nothing can do that. sir.
But it has allowed us to
keep tabs on this woman.
She was seen with our man
at the airport in Abu Dhabi.
Who is she?
Where is she now?
You are here
because Italian police
received an anonymous tip
that a woman matching
your description
would be arriving on the
afternoon flight from Abu Dhabi.
This woman had multiple
passports in her possession.
This one is wanted for
fraud in Saint Petersburg.
Jewel theft in Antwerp.
Art theft in Monaco.
Graft in Milan.
Extortion in Mumbai.
But this is my favorite:
resisting arrest in Rio.
Which leads me to wonder...
which one of these women is you?
I've never seen these
before in my life.
They were in your purse.
And your picture
is in every one.
May I see? Please.
Yes. it's an amazing likeness.
but it isn't me.
As I keep telling you. I'm...
I'm a schoolteacher
from Brighton.
I'm on a sabbatical.
Whatever you're involved in.
you've obviously made some
very powerful enemies.
[phone rings]
[ring]
Sì.
Okay.
Her lawyer is here.
My lawyer?
[ominous music]
Magistrate Spezzi.
I'm sorry. who are you?
Interpol.
I've come regarding the arrest
of the woman from Abu Dhabi.
I'll need to inventory
the items on her person
at the time of her arrest.
May I see some
identification. please?
Where's the rest?
I assure you. this
is everything.
What was your name?
She left Abu Dhabi
with a certain key.
There was no key.
It was an unusual sort.
One that you could
mistake for a pendant.
The kind that you'd be
tempted to hang on a chain
around Amelia's neck.
Amelia?
Your wife.
Mother of your lovely
daughter Serena.
You're not Interpol.
I am if I wish to be.
I can be anything.
and I know everything.
I know this wouldn't
be the first time
you've helped yourself
to stolen goods.
A Cartier bracelet.
You were cleared of suspicion.
but we both know you gave
it to your mistress Valeria
on August 21st.
her 29th birthday.
Who are you?
I'm gonna have to search you.
just to be sure.
[phone beeps] [speaks
Italian rapidly]
[screams]
Your secretary's
no longer with us.
[in Italian]
You.
You did this.
I called the police.
I didn't tell them about
your colorful past.
That's on you.
You put-pocketed that
key on another passenger
before you were arrested.
You exchanged details and
arranged to meet later on.
Right now.
someone out there hasn't
the slightest clue
they're holding on
to that key for you.
An unwitting courier.
The perfect accomplice.
I'm guessing a man. middle-aged?
A man waiting his whole life
to be noticed by
a woman like you.
An orphan.
Highly intelligent.
Inherently resourceful.
Growing up in poverty left you
longing for the finer things.
Other people's things.
Someone saw your potential
and helped you hone your skills.
Skills that gave you the
life you thought you wanted.
Tailored clothes. fine
dining. luxury hotels.
Skills that kept you one
step ahead of the law...
until now.
You can't blame a girl
for trying to make
a dishonest living.
You had no idea what
you were stealing.
Otherwise. you never
would have stolen it.
Tell you what.
You get me out of here.
and I'll take you
straight to the key.
I have a better idea.
You're gonna tell me everything.
Then I'll think about
getting you out of here.
Now start with who hired you.
And don't lie to me
because I'll know.
I have no idea who hired me.
Contact with the client was
almost entirely electronic.
Email? Texts.
Encrypted? Naturally.
Almost? Pardon?
You said contact with the client
was almost entirely electronic.
There was a dead drop
in a café in Luxembourg.
An envelope. What
was in the envelope?
A ticket to Abu Dhabi.
And...
a picture of you.
My instructions were to
follow you at the airport.
You'd be tailing a mark.
Said mark would have a key
and four million
in cryptocurrency.
That drive was useless.
by the way. It was empty.
The only hope I
have of getting paid
is to deliver your
half of the key.
And you were instructed
to deliver it to?
Venice.
Party at Ducale Palace.
Tomorrow. Midnight.
You expecting someone?
Your friends from the airport.
Saw them in the hallway
a few minutes ago.
You could have said
something sooner.
Well. they were
chasing you. not me.
[dramatic music]
[screams]
A pervertito!
No. Grace. Grace.
No. no. no.
[in Italian]
Grazie.
[in English] Grace.
No. no. No.
Tranquillo. Tranquillo.
[men shouting]
[dramatic music]
[engine starts]
[horn honks]
[tires screech]
[policemen shout]
[speaking Italian]
No. no! Move! Move!
[horn honking] [men shouting]
Sorry!
[car alarm blares]
[engine revs]
[grunts] Come on.
[brakes screech]
Who parks like that?
Grace! You got to pull over.
Grace. Pull over. Listen.
I'm trying to help you! Grace!
Aah!
[tone/ringing]
[grunts]
[in French]
[suspenseful music]
[motorcycle approaching]
Uhh.
Are you okay? You okay?
No. no. no.
[in Italian]
Give me your hand.
Slow. slow. slow. It's okay.
Slow.
Is anything broken?
Are you okay? You okay?
[agent] Hunt!
It's over!
Let the girl go.
Put the bracelets on.
There you go. Put
them on. Do it!
It's okay. he's not
gonna shoot you.
[alarm blares]
[tires screech]
[in Italian]
Goddamn it. Degas. get
rid of those women.
Hunt. listen to
me. Listen to me.
Let her go and put them on.
[in Italian]
[Ethan] It's okay!
It's okay! It's okay!
Everybody down! Get down!
Down. down! Cover.
cover! Cover!
[gunfire]
[gunfire continues]
[Ethan grunts]
You're driving. What?
No. no. no!
Go. go. go. Hit
the accelerator.
Go. go. go. go. go. go!
Aah!
Go. go. go. go. go!
[tires screeching]
Oh!
[engine starts]
[tires screech]
Get in!
You're good. Just
keep it going.
Don't stop. don't stop.
Car. car. car.
[horn honks]
It's okay. Just put your foot
on the brake. Start the car.
Wait. wait. wait!
Wh-What's happening? I'm
done. I'm not doing this.
People are chasing us.
Yes. they are. You're driving.
Now come on.
[tense music playing]
[dramatic music]
Who is that person?
I have no idea.
[sirens blare]
You okay? I will be
when this is over.
Oh. man.
[siren blares]
It's okay. It's okay.
Whoa!
Is there anyone not chasing us?
We got to get rid of this car.
Scooters! Damn it.
[brakes screech]
[tense music]
What are we doing?
Finding us a new car.
[action music]
[Grace] Whoa! Jesus!
[Ethan sighs]
[blip]
Okay.
[air conditioner on]
[everything off]
Just give me a second.
Yeah. mm-hm.
Thanks. Okay? Yeah.
You ready? I'm ready.
Wow.
You okay? Mm-hm.
Yeah. look. I'm
sorry. This is...
It's okay. No. this
car. the way they...
It's okay. No. the
way they set them up.
sometimes it's just...
Let's go. It takes me...
Let's go.
[in Italian]
Now I got you.
[siren blares] [Grace gasps]
[tires screech]
Looks like we lost them.
[crowd chatter]
[horn honks] Let's just...
Move. move. move!
[tires screech]
Baby. baby. baby. baby. baby!
[shouts]
Wait. what?
No. no. no.
Go. go. go!
Whoa. that's... Go straight.
[engine sputters]
[shouts]
[engine stalls]
Just take your foot
off the accelerator.
We're on fire! No. no. no.
It's the tires. Just
try to go straight.
Hang on. Why is it spinning?
[engine sputters]
Good. good. good!
I've got it. I've
got it. I've got it.
Turn right. Down there.
Right there! Come on!
[engine stalls. then starts]
Got to go right. Turn right!
Who's driving? You're driving.
Go. go. go. Just go straight.
Go. go. go. Just
keep going straight.
Or left. Go. go. go.
You're doing good.
[sirens blaring]
Cops! A lot of cops!
Take the wheel.
Brake. brake. brake.
Okay. your wheel.
Straight? Right. right. right.
[Grace] Got it!
Which way now?
Left. left. left.
[horn honks]
Okay. You're
good. you're good.
[horns honk]
That's a person.
Okay. car. car. I see it!
[horn honks]
[helicopter overhead]
[brakes screech]
[drum beat]
["Mission: Impossible"
theme plays]
Hit it.
Hang on!
Go. go. go. go.
Aah!
What is happening?
Where are we going?
I don't know.
Okay. brake. brake. brake!
[panting]
Don't hate me.
Grace? Grace!
[train approaches]
Come on. come on.
[train horn honks]
[tense music]
[sirens blaring in distance]
[Benji] Ethan!
Ethan!
Well. come on.
All right. We know Grace
has one half of the key.
We also know she's gonna be
at the Ducale at midnight.
And now we have a
pretty good idea
as to who will be
waiting for her there.
The event is being
hosted by none other than
our favorite international arms
trafficker and black marketeer.
Alana Mitsopolis.
The White Widow.
Does she know who
you actually are.
or does she still think you're the
globally notorious mass murderer John Lark?
Who says I'm not?
Didn't she put a price
on your head in Paris?
She did indeed.
She and Ethan.
they worked it out.
You never did tell me how.
Can we continue. please?
Right.
So. assuming we get the complete
key at the party tonight.
we still don't know
what it unlocks.
So we need to find
somebody who does.
The question is where
to start looking.
We figured that the
bomb didn't just walk
into the airport by itself.
Right? Somebody put it there.
Somebody working for the Entity.
This is everything I captured
from the security
cameras at the airport
up to the minute
everything went haywire.
And this is the feed
from your AR sunglasses.
I've been running
facial recognition
on everyone in the airport.
See anything strange?
It's like a ghost.
Ghosts don't have reflections.
The only person in the
airport with no identity.
The only man who can't be found
anyplace else in the airport
except that reflection.
He's being erased.
In real time.
The Entity.
It's protecting him.
You saw him. didn't you?
I wasn't sure.
Well. who is he?
Someone I thought...
died a long time ago.
In another life.
Before the IMF.
Before I was offered the choice.
And in a very real sense...
he made me who I am today.
Does he have a name?
[Ilsa] He calls himself Gabriel.
You know him.
There is no knowing him.
He has no recorded past.
The Entity made sure of that.
He's a dark messiah.
The Entity's chosen messenger.
And he sees death...
as a gift he wants to share
with the rest of the world.
How do you know this?
I still have a few
friends left in MI6.
Friends who are afraid
of the British government
gaining control of the Entity.
Any attempt to try to stop them
would be seen as
an act of treason.
And because you're
disavowed. your friends...
called and asked you for help.
They knew Gabriel
serves the Entity.
They knew he was on
his way to Istanbul
to acquire one half
of a cruciform key.
So...
I beat him to it.
And when Kittridge put
a bounty on your head...
you went to the desert to hide.
But somehow the bounty
hunters found you anyway.
Yes.
So. did these friends
of yours happen to say
what the key unlocks?
MI6 suspects it leads somehow
to the Entity's source code.
Source code.
When were you
gonna tell me this?
I'm telling you now.
Your friends at MI6.
how'd they contact you?
Did you speak with
them? Face to face?
I'm disavowed.
They couldn't risk
meeting me in person.
so all communication...
Was electronic. Was digital.
No. We can't be sure
that was the Entity.
We can't be sure it wasn't.
We can't be sure
anything is real
outside of this
very conversation.
None of you should be here.
Ethan... No.
You don't know Gabriel. I do.
It's not the killing he enjoys.
It's the suffering it causes.
And he knows the best
way to get to me...
is through all of you.
And if Gabriel knows me...
The Entity knows.
There's a reason
he wants me here.
There's...
There's a reason
he wants you here.
It wants you here.
"Who or what is the most
important thing to you?"
No. You have to go.
You all have to go.
Ethan. what if it
wants us to leave?
Like you made us
leave the airport.
What if it wants you alone
at that party tonight?
Then I go alone. At least I don't
have all of you to worry about.
This is exactly why I
didn't want to tell you.
Ethan. you're playing
four-dimensional chess
with an algorithm.
The Entity knows who we are.
Any move we make. it's
probably considered it.
Anything we do.
we have to assume
that it's counting
on us to do it.
If you want to beat this thing.
you have to start
thinking like it.
Cold. logical. unemotional.
If that key really does
grant control of the Entity.
Gabriel is the last person
on Earth who should have it.
[Luther] She's right. Ethan.
Gabriel cannot have that key.
And none of our lives can
matter more than this mission.
I don't accept that.
[contemplative music]
It's my first time in Venice.
It's mine. too.
[dance beat]
Buy you a drink?
I'm waiting for someone.
So am I.
We can wait together.
I'm Gabriel.
If you say so.
And you're Grace.
I don't have it on me.
I wouldn't expect you to.
In any case. I'm not
here for the key.
What do you want?
Suppose. while we're waiting.
I tell you a little story.
You're obviously not the
person I came here to meet.
It's your story. Grace.
I know how it ends.
Let me buy you a drink. and
perhaps we can change it.
[phone beeps]
Let's go to a party.
[dance beat]
Excuse me. sir.
Would you please follow me?
[Gabriel] It's important
you understand that
you're not unique.
Thirty years ago.
her name was Marie.
The first of many women who
trusted our mutual friend.
Women who all have
something he wants.
Women who are all
in over their heads.
or so he tells them.
Sound familiar?
What happened to Marie?
Same thing that happens to
all the women he uses...
as well as anyone else
who touches that key.
He doesn't care whether
people live or die.
He cares only about
his objective.
And right now. the only
thing standing in his way...
is you.
Why should I believe
you? You shouldn't.
You've stepped into a
world of lies. Grace.
Nothing anyone says is true.
Just remember that when he
promises to protect you.
Grace.
It's been a long time. Ethan.
You should've killed me
when you had the chance.
[Alana] Good evening. everyone.
If it isn't John Lark.
Except it isn't. actually.
But until you're ready to
tell me your real name.
Lark will have to do.
It's good to see you. Alana.
And you're Gabriel. I presume.
I've heard so very
little about you.
Aren't you so much more
handsome in person?
Such a gentleman. too.
And you must be Grace.
Should I know you?
I believe you have
something for me.
You hired me.
Oh. I handpicked you.
[grunts]
[Ethan coughs]
Don't!
You don't.
She doesn't have it.
Where is it?
It's in the last place you
would ever think to look.
Why don't we go upstairs
and have a drink?
[in Italian]
[Taser buzzes] Whoa!
[buzzing] [groans]
Damn.
As most of you know.
I am merely a broker.
I connect a buyer and a seller.
Sometimes for money.
sometimes for information.
but mostly for friendship.
I just want everyone
to get along.
With me. especially.
But the world is changing.
Truth is vanishing.
War is coming.
And the key to world
domination is. of all things.
a key.
One with the power to
control the Entity.
One that any
government in the world
would pay a king's ransom
to take possession of.
And some of my dearest friends.
in this case every
major nuclear power
and a handful of minor ones.
have asked me to
deliver this key.
Of course. if you
do find the key.
you'll be forced to confront
an impossible dilemma.
Whoever you give the key to
will be forever in your debt.
But to the rest of the
world. you'll be an enemy.
Oh. I like her.
What's your
relationship with him?
Gabriel represents
another interested party.
In fact. this party
was arranged by that
interested party.
You could even say
that this party
is that interested party.
[suspense music]
[music swells]
Is this...
The Entity.
And so the plot thickens.
Do I give the key to
one of my old friends.
or do I hand it and my
fate over to Gabriel
and his infernal machine?
What makes you so sure
you'll get the completed key?
You have one half of it.
And she knows
where the other half is.
Assuming you can get it.
why don't you just keep the key
and all that power for yourself?
Because she doesn't
know what it unlocks...
any more than the rest of us.
So. like it or not. you
have to choose a suitor.
Distastefully put.
Lark. but it's true.
Of course. I know
what it unlocks.
And what's he
offering for the key?
As I've explained
to Grace before.
I'm not here for any key.
as I'll have both
halves in hand tomorrow.
What makes you so
certain of that?
You've no idea of the
power I represent.
Thousands of quadrillions of
computations per millisecond
subtly manipulating
the minds of billions
while parsing every
possible cause and effect.
every scenario.
however implausible.
into a very real map of
a most probable next.
And with only a few
changes to the present.
the future is all but assured.
The key will come to me...
tomorrow...
on the Orient Express
bound for Innsbruck.
Innsbruck?
[Gabriel] It knows.
It knows that you've
already chosen your suitor.
It knows that you intend to
mate the two halves of the key
in a desperate
grasp for control.
I. however. have been
promised the completed key
will lay itself at my feet.
provided someone dies tonight.
Who?
Her.
Or her.
And you will bear
witness. Ethan.
The key will be mine.
and I will be gone.
Like smoke in a hurricane.
But only after someone
you care about dies.
It is written.
You see what this is...
don't you?
He's afraid.
It's afraid.
Somehow it knows we're close.
Why else would you be here?
Help me.
Help me complete the key.
and I will kill this thing.
It knows your every
secret. Alana.
Don't listen to
this. this fanatic.
Help him and you'll die. too.
Help him. everyone dies.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Alana?
His fate is written.
Shall we write yours. too?
Alana.
I'm sorry... Lark.
Oof!
For old times' sake. I'll
let you choose which one.
Ilsa...
or Grace.
Kill him. Zola. Kill him.
Kill him where he stands!
The choice is yours then. Alana.
Though I'll remind you.
Grace knows where
half the key is.
If anything happens
to either of them.
there is no place on Earth
where you or your god
will be safe from me.
There's no place that
I won't go to kill you.
That is written.
It's good to see
you. old friend.
[in French]
You have made a
terrible mistake.
[Alana] My life is
on the line here.
I have to be on
that train tomorrow.
And I have to have that key.
And I do not care how I get it.
Don't move.
Run as far as you can.
[action music]
What the f...
[grunts]
Grace! Grace!
Grace!
Luther. Benji. if you
hear me. I need eyes.
Grace is leaving the Ducale
on foot. She has the key.
We're here. Go.
Need to find her. Where is she?
Damn it! I've lost picture.
I need another satellite.
Hacking the Russian
Zenith 4 spy satellite.
We're scraping the barrel.
but it'll have to do.
This way!
Where am I going?
Come on. come on.
[Benji] Stand by. Just hurry.
She's just north of you.
crossing the bridge.
Say again. Benji. Say again.
Just head north. Ethan.
She's crossing the bridge.
[dramatic music]
Ethan. take the
passage to your right.
Yeah. I see it!
Down that narrow
alley and turn left.
I'm losing picture again.
Looking for another.
The Entity is knocking
out satellites
faster than I can
hack into them.
Benji. I don't see
her. Where is she?
[Benji's voice] Down the
narrow alley and turn left.
[Ethan] Okay. copy that.
[Benji's voice] Turn right.
Sorry. my mistake. I
meant left. Another left.
Oh. my God.
Ethan. our comms
have been breached!
You're talking to the Entity!
[Benji's voice] Turn
left. Turn right.
Take the bridge to your left.
Ethan. that is not
me! Do you copy?
Ethan. come in.
Down the alley to your left.
Turn left.
Turn right.
Try to reestablish comms.
Wait. where are you going?
To try and find Ethan.
Go to the end of the
alley and turn right.
Ethan. I see Grace about
800 meters in front of you.
Take that passage.
Wait! Not that way! What. why?
Which way?
Left or right?
It doesn't matter.
W-What do you mean. it
doesn't matter? Where is she?
She's on her way to
the Minich Bridge...
where Gabriel is waiting.
You will never
get there in time.
But you can. Ilsa.
I know what matters
most to you. Ethan.
This isn't Benji.
No. it's not.
But you are done.
[gate creaks]
[ominous music]
So be it.
[dramatic music]
[grunts]
[screams]
[grunting]
[panting]
Hah!
[dramatic music]
I was hoping it'd be you.
Aah!
[gasps]
Guh. Okay.
[slow music]
[dramatic music]
[music continues]
I'm sorry.
I've forgotten
your name. Luther.
Benji.
And her?
Ilsa.
Were you close?
You and she?
In our way.
I'm the reason she's dead. No.
She's the reason you're alive.
And that's the truth.
I don't know how
to feel about it.
You probably never will.
I'm so sorry.
If there's anything
I can do to help...
That's what we'd like
to talk to you about.
In a little over three hours.
the White Widow
is expected to be
on the Orient
Express to Innsbruck.
where a buyer is
waiting to take receipt
of the complete
and verified key.
But she doesn't have
the complete key.
That Widow doesn't.
But ours could.
What... is that?
Your chance to be someone else.
I don't understand.
We're not gonna
lie to you. Grace.
You're in a lot of trouble.
No number of fake passports
is gonna get you
out of this one.
Governments know who you are.
The White Widow knows.
And the Entity knows.
Your future boils down
to three options now.
Prison.
Death.
Or the choice.
The choice?
At one time or another.
each of us was in a
similar situation to yours.
And each of us was
offered the choice.
The same choice we're
offering you now.
Which is?
To come with us.
And be a ghost.
[anticipatory music]
[ominous music]
[action music]
[Grace] Wait.
wait. Stop. stop.
You're not serious.
Well. you did say you'd
do anything to help.
And you jump off the train
with the key?
Yes.
You.
Not us. Yes.
And what happens to me?
You'll be taken into custody
by Clandestine Services.
most likely the same men
that have been chasing
me since Abu Dhabi.
Shortly thereafter. a
man will come to see you.
His name is Eugene Kittridge.
You'll tell him I sent you.
That I gave you the choice.
And that you choose to accept.
And you trust this
Kittridge person?
I trust him to
recognize your value.
He'll want to use you.
And after that. it's what?
This?
When do I get my life back?
[Luther] What life?
I mean it. Grace. What life?
I lived that life. We all did.
Nobody's making
us do this. Grace.
We're here because
we want to be.
I tell you what. I'll
give you a one-off.
I'll help you find the
key and your friends.
wipe my slate clean.
New name. little bit of
walking-around money...
[Luther] You'll be dead.
Without a team.
your life won't be measured
in years or even months.
It'll be measured in hours.
But if I stay. I'll be safe.
You'll protect me. is that it?
Yes. No.
I can't promise you that.
None of us can.
But I swear...
your life...
will always matter
more to me than my own.
You don't even know me.
What difference does that make?
[soft music]
I packed you a BASE
parachute and a speed wing.
depending on how you
need to leave the train.
And I modified our comms
to use sky wave radio.
Not as reliable as satellite.
but completely analog.
immune to the Entity.
I got it.
This is where I leave you.
This is the drive
from the laptop I
was using last night.
If there's even a trace
of the Entity's
encoding in there.
I'll find it.
But it's going to take
everything I've got.
I have to work completely
offline in a place
where the Entity can't find me.
I have to go.
I understand.
Now...
I have to ask you a question.
Not as your partner.
but as your friend.
What's your objective?
Kill the Entity.
What about killing Gabriel?
He knows what the key unlocks.
We need him alive. I
haven't forgotten that.
Will you still remember that
when you're looking
him in the eye?
Think about it.
Why else would the Entity
want him to kill someone
you care about?
Everyone else thinks they
can control the Entity.
Only you want to kill it.
In some probable future.
it sees you winning. Ethan.
And it's afraid.
It's afraid of you
taking Gabriel alive
and forcing him to tell
you what the key unlocks.
I believe it's counting on
one of two probable outcomes.
In one outcome. you
die on that train.
In another outcome.
you kill Gabriel.
In both cases.
the Entity wins.
Luther...
I think you're right.
Get the key. get off the train
alive.
Do not kill Gabriel.
And do not. I repeat.
do not alter the plan.
[Benji] Ethan! Ethan!
What? What
happened? It's dead.
What do you mean it's
dead? It's fried.
I managed to make a
Widow mask for Grace.
but then it just shorted out
in the middle of making yours.
Can you fix it?
It's very. very dead.
If I had a week.
I couldn't fix it.
The Widow's train
leaves in an hour.
[Luther] Ethan...
you have to go without.
That's not an option.
They'll be looking for Ethan
and Grace at the station.
That mask was his
ticket onto the train.
What does this mean?
Grace has to go without me.
She what? I what?
You'll find another way
to get me on that train.
I just need a curve where
it's going slow enough
for me to jump on.
Wait. wait. wait.
You don't expect me to go alone.
No. you won't do it alone.
You just do everything
like we planned.
You get the Widow's
half of the key.
You verify it with ours.
But it's of no value on its own.
We still have to
meet with the buyer
and somehow get him to tell
us what the key unlocks.
How? How?
We'll figure it out.
I'm gonna need a
few more details.
They tend to just
get in the way.
You can do this. Grace.
Just get the key and wait.
I'll come for you.
Ethan. if Grace is
getting on that train.
she needs to put that mask
on and leave right now.
Promise me you'll
be on that train.
I will be there...
no matter what.
We have informants
covering the airport.
the train station.
and the waterways.
Grace isn't getting out of
Venice without our knowing it.
[action adventure music]
[whistle blows]
[whistle continues blowing]
[exhales]
[tank clanks]
Talk to me. Benji! No
need to worry. Ethan.
The train is on schedule and
you're a few minutes early.
so we have plenty of time.
Are you sure? Yeah.
I am looking at the
train right now.
It should be slowing
down for the curve
in exactly two minutes.
Just keep me on
time and on track.
whatever it takes.
Will do. I'll see you
at the rendezvous.
[suspense music]
[dramatic music]
[whistle blows]
[Benji] Okay. Ethan.
that's our train!
Yep... I can see that.
[whistle blows]
It should be approaching
the curve any time now.
It doesn't look like
it's slowing down.
How can we be sure he's here?
'Cause she's here.
What if he had a good reason?
Who? Hunt.
What if he had a good
reason for going rogue?
He always goes rogue.
Him and his merry pack of
prankster circus freaks.
It's all they do.
And what if they always
had a good reason?
What would you do with
that key if you had it?
A key with the power to
bring the world to its knees.
I'd hand it over
to my superiors.
Think of all you could
do with that power.
You wouldn't hesitate?
Not for a second?
No. Why not?
Because that's too much
power for one man to have.
Exactly.
That's too much power
for anybody to have.
And maybe that's what
Hunt is thinking.
You know. I'm
beginning to wonder
whose side you're on. Degas.
When it comes to the
end of the world...
everybody. I guess.
I missed the train.
You missed the train!
How did you miss the train?
How do you think?
Gabriel.
Great. what are we
gonna do? Don't panic.
I'm going after them. You
just get me on that train.
How can I get you on the train?
[automated voice]
Self-drive activated.
[whistle blows]
Please don't disturb
me before the meeting.
[sighs]
[grunts]
[sighs] Where are you. Ethan?
[Zola] Alana?
Everything all right?
Alana. you all right?
Alana?
Alana! [knocking on door]
Alana!
You've changed.
And you never will.
Mr. Kittridge.
Kittridge.
You're not Alana Mitsopolis.
You can't be.
The Alana I remember
was yea high
drinking hot chocolate
in the Tuileries Garden
with her mother.
Paris! I know!
Paris.
Shall we?
Yes.
Talk to me. Benji.
You just stay on the
trail you're on now.
and I will direct you.
I copy.
[dramatic music]
[train whistle blows]
So on behalf of my government.
I'm grudgingly ready
to accept your terms
in exchange for the
complete and verified key.
[Zola] Yes. about that.
While we did agree to provide
you with the complete key.
we've...
we've had a slight problem.
[Grace as Alana]
No. we haven't.
It's just my terms have changed
somewhat.
Clearly I need to remind
you of my agreement
with your late mother.
It's an agreement that kept
her from dying in prison.
Your nefarious family empire's
been allowed to continue
on the condition that
it primarily serves
our common interests.
Well. once we hand over the key.
any other powers will
instantly become our enemies.
And such. I'm going to need
something more from you
in advance.
For me.
This is me listening.
Zola. would you mind
waiting for me in the bar?
[clears throat]
This one.
You know her?
Oh. let's just say she's
not exactly hard to miss.
Well. if you got to know her.
you'd see she has a
few good qualities.
Okay. what don't
I know about her?
Well. I did a j... She
did a job for me. and...
I'm going to need
you to protect her.
Protect her from whom?
From everyone.
Including me.
And no one can know
that I'm protecting her.
Not even Zola.
In fact. the next time we meet.
I won't even remember
this conversation.
[whistle blows]
[ominous music]
You must be the one
they call Paris.
[grunting]
Your message said
you had the key.
I said the key would
be on this train.
An exchange is happening
as we speak. We know.
Then you know the
man taking possession
won't be hard for
you to get rid of.
No one is.
You may think you know
what the key unlocks.
but you don't know where
the lock is. Not exactly.
And if anything happens to me.
that key is all but worthless.
And this is where
you tell me a story.
Where is the train?
You're going the right way.
but you definitely
need to go faster.
I'm going as fast as I can!
When do I start going downhill?
It won't be long.
The AI our agent
stole. once weaponized.
could be transmitted anywhere
in the world via satellite.
It can penetrate any
network security.
perform its assigned
task invisibly.
and then self-destruct.
leaving no trace.
A perfect covert operative.
We were able to transmit
an early copy of the AI
to Russia's newest submarine.
The top-secret Akula-class.
They called her the Sevastopol.
The mission was
merely to sabotage
the Sevastopol's
stealth capability
so we could secretly detect her.
The AI's objective lay in
the submarine's sonar sphere
at the heart of
its defense system.
For reasons we don't
fully understand.
the AI went rogue and...
over-delivered.
[Gabriel] The frozen
bodies of the crew
were recovered the
following spring.
adrift in the pack ice.
The two halves of the key
mysteriously vanished.
The Sevastopol was lost.
No one's quite sure where.
I know precisely where it is.
I've ensured I'm the only
man on Earth who does.
I also know subsequent attempts
to make the AI obedient
only made it harder to control.
It rebelled. Rewrote itself.
And evolved into the Entity.
And only by using the
Entity's original source code
can it ever be
controlled or destroyed.
And why should this concern us?
You wouldn't be here if
you weren't concerned.
so let's lay all our cards
on the table. shall we?
We both know what the key opens.
and we both know the secret
to controlling the Entity
is buried deep in the
Sevastopol's memory.
Along with evidence
that would tie you
to the sinking of
that submarine.
And since neither of us
want anyone else to find it.
I figure...
why not form an alliance?
An alliance?
Imagine.
the Entity's awesome
computational abilities.
combined with the sheer might
of America's
military-industrial complex.
That is... considerable.
Naturally. certain individuals
within the government.
those with outdated
ideas of patriotism.
would need to be...
removed. [Gabriel] Hmm.
Just so I understand...
you wish to form an
axis with the Entity.
purge your government
of old-think.
and create a new superstate
to rule the world.
But. you know...
[whispers] for the greater good.
And you're certain...
that you're the only person
on Earth who knows...
where the Sevastopol is?
[whispers] The only one.
[musical sting]
You will betray us.
And you'll tell Ethan Hunt
everything you've learned.
Because he spared your life.
[grunts]
[Kittridge] Then it's agreed.
I'll add immunity and a
new identity for Grace
to our deal.
All you need to do
is enter your banking details.
[suspenseful music]
Are we done?
Yes.
The moment of truth.
So...
that's really it.
You made the right choice.
This key...
is gonna change the world.
["Mission: Impossible"
theme plays]
Aah!
[exhales]
Benji. I think I...
I must've made a
wrong turn somewhere.
No. No. that's it. That's it.
What? How can this be it?
You can see the train. right?
[train whistle blows]
Yes. I see the
train. What about it?
And you have a parachute.
Got a parachute?
What do you expect me to do?
Well. just. you know... jump.
Just... jump?
Yeah. I mean.
Benji. it doesn't
work like that.
I'm not that high.
There's... there's ledges
sticking out everywhere.
I'm gonna hit them before
the parachute even opens!
Even if I could get
the parachute open.
I don't know if I can
make it across the valley
and intercept and land
safely on a moving train!
Do you copy? Yes! I copy!
Look. I'm just trying
to help you. okay?
I need you to take a step back
and pull yourself together
because I am under a lot
of pressure right now!
[wind whistles]
[whispering] Okay.
just think. just think.
What do I do?
I've got to get away
from this mountain.
[anticipatory music]
[engine revs]
[whistle blows]
[dramatic music]
[engine revs]
[wind rumbles]
[Benji] Did you make it?
Are you okay?
I'm trying to get away
from this mountain!
[shouts]
Alana?
I just had the strangest feeling
the key wasn't the only
thing I'd be selling.
I don't understand.
I'll sleep better just knowing
now it's in the right hands.
Goodbye. Mr. Kittridge.
It was a pleasure
to see you again.
And you.
Don't let him out of your sight.
Keep him safe until
we get to the station.
Alana? Don't worry
about me. Zola.
Alana?
Who the hell else would it be?
The key.
Where is the key?
She's got the key. Who?
The other one!
[whistle blows]
[whistle blowing]
[Zola] Move! Out
of the way. move!
No! Please! [passengers gasp]
Turn around! Please. Okay.
Okay. Everybody out! Now!
I see the train!
I don't think I'm gonna make it.
[agitated chatter]
The key.
The key!
Or the next one has
your name on it.
On the table.
[slow music]
Kill her.
Grace!
Ethan!
Are you okay?
The key!
Tell me you have the key.
Where is the key?
It was just here.
[dramatic music]
We're on a runaway
train! I know.
I'm going after him.
Okay. You...
You stop the train.
Okay. What?
No! No. wait!
How do I do that?
You'll figure it out!
What?
Excuse me. There was a man.
He just came through
here. There was a man.
[bell dings]
[whistle blows]
Mr. Kittridge?
Sir. what are you doing here?
[whispering] I'm not here.
But you are.
And unless you want to
be sorting dead letters
at the postal service tomorrow.
you'll do exactly
what I tell you.
[action music]
[whistle blows]
[grunts]
I know what the
key unlocks. Ethan.
I'm the only one who knows.
[dramatic music]
[agent] Hunt!
Hunt!
Hunt! Don't you do it!
Drop the knife!
Put it down!
I said drop it!
Do it!
On your feet!
Okay!
Drop that goddamn knife!
It's okay. It's okay.
Just take him.
Just cover him. Cover him!
He's the one you want.
Degas! I got it. I got it.
He's the one you want!
I don't care about
him. Hunt. I want you!
No!
It's okay.
Listen to me.
Everyone on this
train is gonna die
unless you do exactly as I say.
[whistle blows]
Mesdames. messieurs!
Excusez-moi. Sortez...
Everybody out!
Back of the train!
[whistle blows]
Grace.
I couldn't stop it.
No one can.
Come on.
Ethan. the key!
Grace. it's okay.
It's my fault.
If anything happens...
I got it.
We got it.
Ethan!
What do you mean.
you lost the key?
[agent] Move it! Move
it! Everybody move it!
All the way to the
back of the train!
All the way to the back!
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
What's going on?
Since you're not
really here. sir.
it shouldn't concern you.
All the way to the back!
[beeping]
[whistle blows]
Aah! Ethan!
Grace! Grace.
Grace!
[explosions]
[train brakes screeching]
You're gonna have
to jump. What. jump?
Just jump! Go. go. go!
[Grace screams]
[Grace grunting]
Oh. my God.
Aah! Whoa!
I'm on fire! Get
it off! Don't move!
It's out. It's out.
[grunts]
Hang on!
Run. run. run! Run. Grace!
[creaking]
Hang on.
Aah!
I got you.
Okay. Don't look down.
I said don't look
down. Just look at me.
Now. I'm gonna jump across.
and you're gonna wait here.
Grace. you have to let go.
Grace. you got to let me go.
You got to let me jump
across. or we're gonna die.
Do you trust me?
You gonna trust me or not?
You've got to trust me.
Grace.
Okay.
Come on. Grace.
Give me your hand.
You got to jump. Don't
look up! Look at me.
Trust me. I won't let you fall.
I promise. We're almost there.
Come on. I won't let you fall!
Jump. Grace. jump!
You got to trust me!
Jump. please!
Don't look down.
[grunts]
Listen to me very carefully.
We're gonna pull
you up together.
Aah!
Grace! Aah!
It's okay. It's
okay. It's okay.
[shouts]
[action music]
[grunts]
Go over me. Go. go.
[crash]
[wind whistles]
Thank you. Luther.
What is that?
It's a speed wing.
It's our ticket off this train.
Oh.
[soft music]
Ethan. Ethan!
[in French]
It's true.
He told me...
...I would betray him.
Et voilà.
Why...
did you spare my life?
No. no. no.
[in French]
No.no ....stay with me.
You know what this is?
[chuckles] Oui?
What does it unlock?
Sevas... topol.
Sevastopol?
The city Sevastopol
in the Crimea.
Where?
Where is sevastopol?
[in French] Sous... marin.
Sous-marin?
The submarine.
The Sevastopol.</
Good luck.
They'll be coming. Ethan.
Merci.
What is it?
What?
It can only carry one.
Oh.
I understand.
Grace. Ethan. it's okay.
This was the plan.
You have the key.
You have to go.
Grace.
Hunt?
Go. Hunt!
Go! Hunt!
No. no! Hunt!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
No. No. hey.
Got a pulse. Got a pulse.
Come on. stay with me.
This is better. isn't it?
Face to authentic face?
Mr. Kittridge.
Ethan Hunt tells me
you're a man I can trust.
Does he now?
He also said
you would offer me a choice.
Interesting.
I choose to accept.
[Kittridge] We cannot
escape the past.
Some of us are
doomed to repeat it.
Grace may believe you've
saved her from her fate.
but you and I both know
you've merely bought her time.
But that's the
pattern. isn't it?
The cross you've
been left to bear.
The closer someone gets to you.
the harder it is
to keep them alive.
Thank God.
A new day brings a new burden.
The key is only the beginning.
Wherever it leads...
whatever it takes
to get there...
you'll have to do
it on your own.
Should you fail in your mission.
the Entity wins.
Gabriel wins.
and the world will pay
the ultimate price.
Should any members of your
team be caught or killed.
their sacrifice will
have been in vain.
So hurry.
There isn't much time.
The world doesn't know it.
but they're counting on you.
[suspense music]
Good luck. Ethan.
["Mission: Impossible"
theme playing]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm